IL Cafe we have you
covered hello and welcome to Il Cafe
today we're going to talk aboutme
insurance and the context to that is
this one India has 63 million msmes
spread across it and they've been
contributing uh nearly 40% of overall
exports in India now the penetration
rate of General insurance for non-life
insurance in India was 9% in the fiscal
year of 2019 which increase from
0.6% in 2009 so that's the background
and growth that we talking about so
clearly I mean as is evident this is
quite an uphill task for insurers like
icso Lombard um to close the gap that
exists and also engage with smmes very
very effectively so yes that is what
we're going to be doing on I Cafe today
welcome to the show this is Shel and the
person that I have joining us on the
show to help us understand the space a
bit better is Fe Ed and he is an
insurance professional with over two
decades of experience behind him he's
also currently the vice president agency
at ICS y lomad so who better than him to
tell us a little bit more about this and
he also describes by the way himself as
a distribution evangelist through
insurance brokers and advisers and is
working towards realizing the potential
of retail and smmes so thank you so much
aair for joining us on I Cafe and
welcome to the show how are you thank
you for giving me an opportunity to be a
part of this discussion thanks thanks a
lot the first question has to do with
the efforts that the government has
increased towards promoting technology
upgradation Financial liquidity Market
linkages skill upgradation all of these
which are typically challenges for msmes
and these have been really working
wonders so does that really mean that
the coming year is going to see exciting
times ahead of us because I keep
wondering why insurance doesn't really
get the same level of attention and what
can be done to spread the word PHS yeah
certainly I think the very beautiful
question that we really coin and asked
me so I'll tell you if you look at the
situation the unfortunate part is that
not not many smmes are aware of the
business exposures that they carry in
terms of their risk when they are you
know doing in a particular industry and
uh and hence the insurance becomes a
last priority for them to be a part of
their overall uh business discussions
right and that is the only reason why
they exposed to such risk which probably
become a financial issue at the end of
the day for them few things which comes
to my mind apart from the government
intervention I'm sure government is
doing their part but yes now the and
msme trade ass associations they also
play a very very vital and pivotal role
when you start discussing about their
own members well-being their own
wellbeing in terms of the exposure
that's something which is important for
them to do banks now have again started
doing it very aggressively and I'm sure
Banks has a larger penetration which
will ultimately help all of us in
reaching the last mile of smmes thirdly
uh you rightly mentioned about the
government initiatives yes the
government are taking initiative live
example that I can give you at at this
point in time the Maharashtra
government's initiative about insuring
all the you know shop establishments in
maharash is a draft that they have
rolled out right that is a very
beautiful way forward for the
governments to intervene and similar
kind of a setup has been done by Kerala
government also when they're giving a
subsidy to buy our insurance policy for
the smmes and msmes registered there so
that is a kind of movement that has
really triggered up in the in the past
couple of months and I'm sure uh so
India is a hub of larger smmes and it
will go a long way uring them right and
I like the positive uh note that you
have spun over here for us and yet you
know the sector we noticed right was
quite severely affected due to the
liquidity crunch that happened when the
pandemic really hit us and just to give
a context to our viewers that sector is
estimated to be around 42 million plus
registered and unregistered companies
that drive about 95% of the Total
Industrial units in India so that's the
size that we're looking at and if
anything covid-19 has taught us the the
need to be prepared for the unexpected
that I think is our biggest takeaway uh
in addition to our focus on our health
uh but in general in recognition of the
sector's contribution to the economy I
would imagine should be focusing on
insurance so what are the benefits that
will AC to smmes if they do consider
insurance if you look at the Domain the
small and medium Enterprises are
actually exposed to a lot of potential
threats and that could impact the
operations their assets the entire
Financial wellbeing and probably it has
a it has an exposure to shut shops right
and in this particular domain insurance
can really play a very very pivotal role
in safeguarding their interest right
it's a very critical tool because
ultimately you are transferring the risk
to an insurance company which is going
to help you at the time of any natural
disaster or any Calamity or anything
which comes to order in terms of
financial you know uptake that is point
number one uh if I give you some
classical examples what what do we I see
when I talk about insurances uh see one
the very classical uh you know product
we call it the property insurance which
products which protects the you know
buyer from physical assets their
buildings their equipments their plant
and machineries for against Natural
Disasters theft fire or any such
incident coming their way they can be
safeguarded then they have a business
Interruption going on where probably if
you are you know failing to deliver your
promises to your end buyer and you have
a business uh Interruption cover taken
then business Interruption cover can
help you in compensating that loss that
you could have incurred there that is
something which is again important then
again the labor Ministry asked to cover
their workers as well so that is how the
insurance policy which is workers
compensation policy help there uh the
well-being of the workers working in a
particular unit which is a manufacturing
setup or any other setup for that matter
I'm sure every day in a newspaper we now
keep hearing about uh the Cyber threats
right so cyber is a new threat that
probably now msmes are exposed to cyber
insurance now protects them against the
Cyber threats so there are multiple
product lines for export oriented unit
if I give you a very classical example
uh the goods that they Transit from one
location to the other destination it has
a lot of exposures right and they also
want it to reach at the particular
destination safely so they can also
ensure them in terms of Transit
Insurance exposure that they carry so
there are multiple lines of business
insurances that really helps all these
msmes Andes to safeguard their interest
and post pandemic it has become all the
way more critical and crucial because at
the end of the day it is money which is
there on the stake you know one other
thing and you brought that up over there
right from the point of view of the
employees of these msmes ormes um we've
seen obviously individuals taking a lot
more cognizance of their own health
especially post pandemic it's always
been there but nevertheless pandemic has
seen an uptick in that Focus uh but
organizations also for many reasons are
now putting employee well-being at the
center of all that they do whether it is
mental health or physical health uh
whether it is conducting workshops and
yoga and you know we hear so much of the
employee being at the center of that
particular universe and I think the
younger people also right the younger
part of the workforce is quite
interested in joining organizations that
appear to be caring for their wellbeing
and not just your career or professional
growth so in that context right
organizations that offer group health
insurance that's one of the categories
that I want to focus on over here tell
us about the benefits for a company that
takes group health insurance of as yeah
so if you look at the current situation
in the country uh the cost of medical
hospitalization is increasing every
passing years like uh like anything if
you look at the percentage growth I is
25 20 20% inflation that we seen a
medical cost uh triggering in the
hospital ization it's a huge cost it's a
huge outgo right so now thees have
started realizing the importance of
medical cost which really hits the
employees at the end over the day right
so now smmes have started offering their
employees the health insurance benefit
right the beauty of this plan uh when
you talk about s taking a plan versus
individual taking a plan there's a
there's a kind of difference that we
have in the coverages and etc for
example when you buy a corporate
insurance plan or insurance plan you
have an option of covering all the
pre-existing ailments from day one that
is the option that you can explore in it
it also can add a benefit of maternity
for the you know female employees or the
spouses of the employees right so at the
end of the day from the employer side
it's a employee benefit tool right and
it it acts as a wonderful uh you know uh
uh wonderful angle when you talk when
you talk about your probably retaining
your employees or giving them some
benefits because there a lot of time
when people feel that okay am I really
being Cared by my organization so this
is one of the tool by the HR employee
benefit site yes you are being
absolutely more most privileged lot
working with us as an organization it's
beautiful Tool uh the second addition to
this I'll say is a accidental benefit so
more than hospitalization yes it is
important aspect but accidental
disabilities or death of a employee
again is a very very uh you know
challenging thing to cover there's a
policy which covers a group accidental
uh feature of a particulares right and
the employees get covered in it so
combination of medical insurance which
is health insurance and accidental
coverage gives a Wonder wonderful
wonderful coverage as a benefit tool
that is something which is now picked up
very very rapidly now the other area you
again had dropped that up as when you
spoke about the different offerings that
we have over here you spoke about cyber
security and that's a huge area right
across businesses across sectors so in
this particular case if a company Falls
victim to a cyber threat or an attack uh
does IC lombar have any product or
solution for this sort of a scenario
some sort of insurance coverage perhaps
so yes there's a possibility of uh you
know covering your cyber threat exposure
for example if somebody you know hacks
into a system and gets your data deleted
or hack your data or something on those
lives happens it's a big big uh you know
Financial loss for organizations right
so we at icar certainly has a policy
which is uh I can I can categorize into
two formats so one of the policy covers
a retail part of a you know exposure for
example as an individual if you want to
cover my cyber threats because we have
exposed to using mobile phones internet
and so on and so forth we are exposed to
it we can cover our individual interest
also as an organization smmes and msmes
if they want to cover their cyber threat
in their own system yes it is
possibility to cover their own cyber
exposures as well so now the product is
available in the country and the uptake
of the product is phenomenal because at
the end of the day you can Safeguard
such risk which probably people sitting
anywhere in the world can you know just
attack your systems I think nothing like
it so I guess this there's a doability
of covering both the things to gain that
way now I'm coming to one more area and
uh we briefly sort of skimmed over this
as well but again details would be very
useful any aspect of a of running a
business involves an element of
logistics right and every year companies
incur several losses on account of non-
delivery accidents misplacements Etc in
this context is there something that you
offer msmes who need to ensure or
protect themselves uh against the sort
of
eventuality yeah so I touched upon my
earlier coverages but I'll give you a
more elaborated version now uh see uh
Marine Transit is a part of format which
largely covers your risk related to
logistics for example if you are an
export oriented unit and you are you
know transporting your goods from one
destination to the other one port to
other Port yes there's a lot of exposure
that comes because there are multiple
legs that gets changed within the
country or probably in the country you
are sending your goods for right and at
the end of the day it is a it's a you
know sizable exposure because at the end
if the does the goods doesn't reaches
the spot you are liable to uh you know
bear that cost so today the format has
definitely evolved you can cover all the
domestic risk as will probably sending
one uh destination to the other
destination within the country or if you
export unit and you want to export your
goods and sending to other country that
can also be insured it covers your
overturning risk it covers your shortage
non- delivery and lot of other you know
Associated perils with it's a very very
broad format and it's a very old format
of insurance so yes Marine Insurance
plays a very very critical role in
safeguarding that indeed you know
something new that IC Lumbard is
credited with is that website the
digital platform that you've created
Forme business risk coverage we are
almost considered to be Pioneers in the
area so tell us a little bit about this
platform that's available to MSN yeah so
uh yeah thank you so much for giving us
a compliment yeah we absolutely were the
first ones to launch this uh platform in
ic Lombard wherein we call this a
digital probably where the customers and
the buyers can come to the website of IC
Lombard and can buy the insurances which
probably are needed by them the couple
of insurances which are easy formatted
and easy to buy easy to understand we
have kept those as of now for example uh
if you're transiting your good from one
location to other and immediately you
have a need of a policy you can just
simply log into the website of ICS
Lombard and then take the policy
similarly if you have workers you have a
contract being going on and you want uh
workers to be insured in that you can
definitely take a policy from IC Lombard
website so all these small ticket size
policies all the policies which have a
easy understanding by the customers the
customers themselves can go to the
website and buy a policy and it's it's
ease of buying a policy with an
immediate attention to come to the other
aspect of uh you know the story ideally
you know I should have asked this
question right in the beginning but
better late than never right so what is
ICC laas business insurance skater to in
manner of a Target segment who's your
intended audience and who are the
intended beneficiaries of the insurance
business so I think I'll answer it in
two ways first we don't consider it as a
target audience for us these are people
these are customer who are in dire need
of insurances dire need of their risk
which are exposed to be covered and when
we talk about as ICC Lombard as an
institution we have a moral
responsibility to give them the right
coverage right thing so that financially
they are at peace right so for us
there's no target audience there's
nothing no word which exists here yeah
at the end of the day we keep on finding
ways to reach these smes and give them
the solutions that they are looking
ahead because if you ask me today the
awareness of the first topic that you
touched upon the today the problem
statement was awareness right so we
figur out a ways how to reach these
associations these people these smes and
make them aware of the problems
statement that they are facing day in
and day out and give them a solution
which is simplistic to understand rather
than a complex solution which we do not
understand in terms of insurance so that
is how we try to create products in the
company which are simplistic can cover
all the exposure that they exposed in a
single format and when policy can serve
the entire purpose of the you know
particular unit that they run so this is
the kind of approach that we keep as ICS
Al by but if you were to summarize um
and address a specific question in the
mind of perhaps someone who's part of
orun and msme what's in it for me what
is the customer really going to gain
from the proposition that uh this is all
about yeah so uh from the customer point
of view if you honestly ask me uh the
understanding of all the products
practically is not possible for them and
I don't expect the customers to really
want to spend time in it because at the
end of the day their basic core job is
something else in non- inssurance right
so as an insurance the ultimate thing
that we try to uh really take the
journey ahead is giving them a
simplistic insurance comprehensive
policy so for the customer they get one
comprehensive policy which largely
ensures them in various format for
example if your exposure is related to
fire if your exposure is related to
workers if your exposure is related to
liabilities or Marine so one format
really helps them in getting all those
exposures covered in a simplistic way
right that is what we really look ahead
when we talk about what is there in the
customer for the customer it is a
comprehensive package probably which
helps them in getting fully satisfied uh
fully at Sol at the end of the day they
should not put brains they should not
put energy and time in something which
is not their core domain it is an
insurance company domain and a
responsibility of an insurance company
to help them and speaking of help right
helping customers uh that we have this
is other aspect of things you know I'm
just we just at the time of recording
with you we're just hosting the secret
Center sort of Celebration and one has
to buy gifts and I realize for me it's
the ease with which I can buy a gift so
that's the platform or portal that I'm
going to go to where is the most
convenient option available to me
nearest and within the time that I need
these items to be delivered to my office
so everybody's gifting is covered um and
that ease of uh conducting or doing
transactions is what I think every one
of us irrespective of what task it is is
looking forward to uh you've told us
about the digital platform but uh is it
really that simple can you know someone
for example just ensure themselves while
chomping into a sandwich or a piece of
cake so certainly when we designed this
uh portal which is. lomb.com uh the only
thing that we had in mind was keeping
the customer first and see how
convenient it can be for a Layman to buy
a policy right so whatever whatever
clicks that we have kept is keeping in
mind if I don't understand Insurance can
I still buy a policy from ICC Lombard's
portal that was the premise when we
started launching this thing and that
was the whole discussion that we got
originated and today I'll say yes
certainly we've got a bit success there
because at the end of the day we kept
customer first before everything else in
three clicks you can buy a policy it is
that that ease and convenience that we
have tried to build from our side and
that is the Journey that we will
continue as an Endeavor to take ahead
also one last question right um at the
time of recording this podcast we
looking at 2024 with new eyes right any
personal bucket list of things to do I
like to ask all my guests something
personal about themselves anything
things that you've decided you want to
do in the year 2024 bunge jumping scuba
diving learning to play a guitar no I
think uh yes so I'm I'm I'm a marathon
runner right and that is how it keeps me
going right so we have a Mumbai marathon
coming very very near so I'm looking
forward for that barathon that is what
something it's immediately in the card
for me on the on the personal front and
nice you nice to have a health kind of
an angle thrown in over here because I'm
sure part of running a marathon is also
making sure that you're fit you eat
right you work out every day sleep well
all of that is part of the territory and
here's wishing you the very best in the
upcoming marathon Fest and thank you for
joining us on I Cafe thank you so much
it's a wonderful pleasure to speak with
all of you thanks wonderful thanks a lot